followinginmyshoes.com 2018-12-30

# Privacy Policy

This Privacy Policy governs the manner in which Following In My Shoes collects, uses, maintains and discloses information collected from users (each, a “User”) of the https://followinginmyshoes.com website (“Site”). This privacy policy applies to the Site and all products and services offered by Following In My Shoes.

### Who We Are

Our website address is: https://followinginmyshoes.com.  You can learn more about the primary author, Rachel, [here](https://followinginmyshoes.com/rachel_lacy/).

## **All About Data And Why We Collect It**

### Personal Identification Information

We may collect personally identification information from Users in a variety of ways in connection with activities, services, features or resources we make available on our Site. Users may be asked for, as appropriate, their name and email address. We will collect personal identification information from Users only if they voluntarily submit such information to us. Users can always refuse to supply personally identification information, except that it may prevent them from engaging in certain Site related activities (such as giveaways).

Personal data may be collected in a variety of ways such as contact forms, comments, cookies, analytics, and third party embeds.

### Non-Personal Identification Information

Our analytics, etc., may collect non-personal identification information about Users whenever they interact with our Site. Non-personal identification information may include the browser name, the type of computer and technical information about Users means of connection to our Site, such as the operating system and the Internet service providers utilized and other similar information.

### Why We Use Collected Information

Following In My Shoes collects and uses Users personal information for the following purposes:

**– To administer a content, promotion, survey or other Site feature**  
To send Users information they agreed to receive about topics we think will be of interest to them — i.e. to notify giveaway winners.  
**– To send periodic emails**  
The email address Users provide will only be used to respond to their direct inquiries, and/or other requests or questions.

## **How We Collect Information**

### Blog Comments

At this time, we no longer allow comments on posts; if you have a question about a recipe, etc., you may email  directly.

But, with regard to past comments left before they were turned off commenting: when visitors left comments on the site, data shown in the comments form was collected, along with the visitor’s IP address and browser user agent string — all of which was used to help spam detection.

An anonymized string created from those email addresses ( _also called a hash_ ) may have been provided to the Gravatar service to see if the user was using it. The Gravatar service privacy policy is available here: https://automattic.com/privacy/. ( _After approval of those past comment, a user’s profile picture would be made visible to the public in the context of  their comment_.)

### Web Browser Cookies

Our Site may use “cookies” to enhance User experience. User’s web browser places cookies on their hard drive for record-keeping purposes and sometimes to track information about them. User may choose to set their web browser to refuse cookies, or to alert you when cookies are being sent. If they do so, note that some parts of the Site may not function properly.

3rd Party Services used, such as plug-ins, may also use cookies for each user.  At this time, the following 3rd party plug-ins/services are being use on this site:

  * Akismet — _“We collect information about visitors who comment on Sites that use our Akismet anti-spam service. The information we collect depends on how the User sets up Akismet for the Site, but typically includes the commenter’s IP address, user agent, referrer, and Site URL (along with other information directly provided by the commenter such as their name, username, email address, and the comment itself).”_
  * Google Analytics
  * Easy Recipe Plus
  * Contact Form
  * Simple Social Icons
  * Feed burner RSS
  * Instagram Feed WD —  _“Instagram Feed WD plugin uses Instagram API on website front end. All the data received from Instagram via API is cached in WordPress database for some short period to provide front end optimization. You may request us to delete your Instagram data if it is accidentally cached in our website database with hashtag feed data. Instagram saves some cookies in browsers of website visitors via API data. These cookies are mostly used for security purposes. They are regulated under terms of Instagram’s  [Privacy Policy](https://instagram.com/legal/privacy).”_

### Embedded Content From Other Websites

Articles on this site may include embedded content (e.g. videos, images, articles, etc.). Embedded content from other websites behaves in the exact same way as if the visitor has visited the other website.

These websites may collect data about you, use cookies, embed additional third-party tracking, and monitor your interaction with that embedded content, including tracing your interaction with the embedded content if you have an account and are logged in to that website.

### Analytics

Following In My Shoes uses Google Analytics, which uses cookies to record user-specific information on what pages users access or visit and additional stats, to provide comprehensive site audience information and statistics.

### Third Party Websites

We use third-party advertising companies to serve ads when you visit our Web site. These companies may use aggregated information (not including your name, address, email address or telephone number) about your visits to this and other Web sites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services of interest to you. If you would like more information about this practice and to know your choices about not having this information used by these companies, please see: <http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp>

### Advertising

Ads appearing on our site may be delivered to Users by advertising partners, who may set cookies. These cookies allow the ad server to recognize your computer each time they send you an online advertisement to compile non personal identification information about you or others who use your computer. This information allows ad networks to, among other things, deliver targeted advertisements that they believe will be of most interest to you. This privacy policy does not cover the use of cookies by any advertisers.

Currently, Following In My Shoes uses Google AdSense for site ads and Amazon Affiliates for direct product links.

## **How We Protect Your Information**

We adopt appropriate data collection, storage and processing practices and security measures to protect against unauthorized access, alteration, disclosure or destruction of your personal information, username, password, transaction information and data stored on our Site.

Our Site is in compliance with PCI vulnerability standards in order to create as secure of an environment as possible for Users.

### Your Rights Over Your Data

If you have an account on this site, or have left comments, you can request to receive an exported file of the personal data we hold about you, including any data you have provided to us. You can also request that we erase any personal data we hold about you. This does not include any data we are obliged to keep for administrative, legal, or security purposes.

### Sharing Your Personal Information

**We do not sell, trade, or rent Users personal identification information to others.** We may share generic aggregated demographic information not linked to any personal identification information regarding visitors and users with our business partners, trusted affiliates and advertisers for the purposes outlined above.

### How Long Do We Store Data/Information

If you leave a comment, the comment and its metadata are retained indefinitely. This is so we can recognize and approve any follow-up comments automatically instead of holding them in a moderation queue.

For users that register on our website (if any), we also store the personal information they provide in their user profile. All users can see, edit, or delete their personal information at any time (except they cannot change their username). Website administrators can also see and edit that information.

### **Changes To This Privacy Policy**

Following In My Shoes has the discretion to update this privacy policy at any time. When we do, we will revise the updated date at the bottom of this page. We encourage Users to frequently check this page for any changes to stay informed about how we are helping to protect the personal information we collect. You acknowledge and agree that it is your responsibility to review this privacy policy periodically and become aware of modifications.

### **Your acceptance of these terms**

By using this Site, you signify your acceptance of this policy. If you do not agree to this policy, please do not use our Site. Your continued use of the Site following the posting of changes to this policy will be deemed your acceptance of those changes.

### **Contact**

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, the practices of this site, or your dealings with this site, please contact us at:  
Following In My Shoes  
https://followinginmyshoes.com  
College Station, TX  
rachel@followinginmyshoes.com

This document was last updated on May 28, 2018.
